≪木ノ葉のサイが
忍刀を１人　封印したぞ！
Sai of the Hidden Leaf sealed away
one of the Ninja Swords!
《カカシ：サイ　うまくやったようだな。
Looks like you did well, Sai.
このまま　隊の士気を
高く維持できればいいんだが》
I just hope we can
keep morale high.
本部に問い合わせていた
忍刀の情報が届きました。
We've received
the information we wanted
on the Ninja Swordsmen from HQ.
敵の動きが止まっている
今のうちに→
We should gather as much
information as we can
できるだけ多くの情報を
集めておきたいからね。
while the enemy's stopped
all movement.
さすがと言うべきか→
I should have expected it.
They're all quite fearsome.
一筋縄じゃいかない
連中ばかりだな。
《特に　あの２人には
気をつけなければ→
We need to be especially
careful of these two.
集団戦は　こちらが不利に》
We'll be at a disadvantage
in a group battle.
≪た　助けてくれ～！
Help me!
どうした！？
What's wrong?
体が…　糸に操られて！
Strings are controlling my body...
ぐわ～っ！
《糸！？》
Strings?!
ぐわ～っ！
（串丸）フッフッフ。
生きたまま　はりつけにして
苦しむさまを楽しんでやがる！
He's crucifying them alive and
taking pleasure in their suffering...
うわ～っ！
やめろ！
Stop!
やめろ～！
ゲームでも楽しんでいるつもりか！？
Is this some kind of game for you?
（カカシ）ラン！
Ran!
お前たち　許せん！
You are unforgivable!
操られ　不本意な戦闘を
強いられている→
I feel sorry for the legends
of past generations
名のある先代たちを思えば
同情もし　心も痛むが→
who are being forced to fight
against their will.
It pains me...
You revel in killing.
お前らは殺しを楽しんでいる！
同じ忍であることすら嫌悪する。
I hate to think that
we're both called shinobi...
（甚八）フン　何を偉そうに。
Stop being so full of yourself.
誰に断って　そいつを振るう！
Who do you think
you're pointing that at?!
そいつは　俺たち七人衆のもんだ！
That belongs to the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist!
（串丸）よそもんが
首斬り包丁を振るうだと？
An outsider wielding
the Executioner's Blade?
気に入らねえ！
I don't like it one bit!
ソイツは俺の的だ！
He's mine!
《いかに不死身だとしても→
Even though they can't die,
仲間を仲間と思わない。
they don't take each other
into consideration
冷酷非情な攻撃》
when they make
their brutal attacks...
テメエを殺し
首斬り包丁を取り戻す。
I'm going to kill you and take back
the Executioner's Blade!
俺がな。
No, I will.
邪魔するなら
お前から殺すぞ！
I'll kill you if you get in my way!
ヘヘヘッ　もう死んでんぜ。
I'm already dead.
《コイツら相手に２対１は
さすがに厳しいか》
Going up against these two alone
is going to be rough, but...
（ガイ）ピンチのようだな　友よ。
Looks like you're backed up
against a wall, buddy!
木ノ葉！
剛力旋風！
Severe...
Leaf Hurricanes!
木ノ葉の気高き碧い猛獣
マイト・ガイ。
I'm Might Guy,
the Hidden Leaf's Noble Blue Beast!
待たせたな　カカシよ。
Sorry I'm late, Kakashi.
always chasing after your shadow
itsu made mo oikakete iru anata no zanzo wo
when you dream, your face looks like it did before
yume ni miru yokogao ha ano koro no mama de
you run into the tall grass and disappear
se no takai kusanami ni hashiri satte kieta
I push through the memories and follow you
omoidasu kioku wo kakewake atoo uboku ha
it's frustrating as I run out of breath and in the end I'm unable to reach you
modokashiku mo iki wo kirashite saigo ha todokazu ni
far away
tooku
how many years ago was it?
nannenmae no koto desho
I left my heart at that place
nidoto modorenai ano basho ni
where I can never return
oite kite shimatta boku no kokoro sa
if this is a dream, if I can't get it back
moshimo yume naraba tori modosenai no nara
then how can I tell you how I feel?
kono kimochi ha do shite utaereba ii no
I'm still chasing after the shadow from that day
imadani oikakete iru ano hi no zanzo wo
though I spend my days in sorrow
kanashimi ni ake kurenagara mo ima
I'll live on in this world without you
anata naki sekai de boku wa ikiru yo
Danger: Jinpachi and Kushimaru
助かったよ　ガイ。
Thanks, Guy.
うん？
小隊での行動は危険だ。
You're the one who wanted us
to regroup
よって　集合させようと言ったのは
お前自身だぞ。
because it was dangerous
to work in platoons.
１人単独行動して
どうする？
So why are you doing this
by yourself?
え？　しかも相手は
忍刀七人衆　２人ときた。
Furthermore, you're fighting two of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen
of the Mist.
１人でも助けたいと
ムリをした。
I wanted to save as many people
as I could and got in over my head.
そうだろうな…　それより
今のうちに彼女を。
I figured that was the case.
Anyway, we should get her away
from here while we can.
ああ　すまない。
Yeah, thanks.
素直なカカシというのも
気味が悪いな。
It's kind of creepy to see you
being so grateful.
だが　そう思わせるほどの
相手ということか。
But... I guess your opponents were
just strong enough
to make you feel that way.
フフフ。
（ラン）ここは？　はっ！
Where am I?
アイツが　アイツが私の仲間を！
He... He killed my comrades!
わかっている
敵は討ってやるから→
I know.
We're going to defeat
the enemy,
お前は本隊に合流しろ。
so you go regroup with
the main regiment.
しかし…。
B-But...
この敵を相手にするには
足手まといだと言っているのだ。
When we fight them,
you'll only get in our way.
お気をつけて。
Be careful.
さて　よくも我らの仲間を
おもちゃ扱いしてくれたな！
Now then...
How dare you treat our comrades
like they were your toys.
気をつけろ　ガイ。
Be careful, Guy.
長刀　縫い針の
栗霰串丸に→
Kushimaru Kuriarare, who wields
the Long Blade the Sewing Needle...
爆刀　飛沫の無梨甚八。
And Jinpachi Nanashi, who wields
the Explosive Blade, the Splatter...
師匠殺しに兄殺し。
One killed his master and
the other killed his older brother.
その他もろもろ
非情の百貨店みたいなヤツらだ。
Aside from that, they've committed
countless acts of cruelty.
邪魔をするなら　お前も殺す。
ヘヘヘ。
If you get in my way,
I'll kill you too!
コイツら　いわば
非情コンビってところだ。
I guess you could call them
the cold-blooded combo.
気を引き締めていくぞ。
We've got to stay focused!
問題などない。
That's no problem!
ヤツらが非情コンビなら
俺たちは友情コンビだ。
They may be the cold-blooded combo,
but we're the comrades combo!
木ノ葉の友情最強コンビに
かなう敵などないわ！
No one is a match for the Hidden Leaf's
invincible comrades combo!
《フッ　隙だらけだな。
They're open to attack.
俺のスピードもなめられたもんだ！》
They've underestimated my speed.
うお～！
《その仕掛けゆえの大振りか。
しかし》
His swings are big because
of that gimmick. But...
《長刀がない！》
He doesn't have his Long Blade!
気をつけろ！　ガイ！
Be careful, Guy!
うん？
長刀忍法　地蜘蛛縫い！
Ninja Art Long Blade!
Stitching Spider!
ふんっ　ぬお～！　こんなもの！！
This thing!
うお～っ！
爆刀術！　発破勒重死！
Explosive Blade Jutsu!
Multiple Explosions of Death!
ガイ！
Guy!
俺は　いい！　貴様は逃げろ！
Don't mind me! Get out of here!
また助けられたな。　カカシよ。
You saved me again, Kakashi.
((土遁　多重土流壁！))
Earth Style! Multi Mud Wall!
いや　俺が甘かった。
I was naïve.
忍刀七人衆のデータを
頭に入れてるつもりが→
I thought I had all the data
on the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist...
不死であることを
あそこまで利用して→
But I never expected them to take
advantage of being reanimated that well.
戦闘に活かしてくるとはな。
お前　まさか…。
Kakashi? Did they...
ああ　目をやられたようだ。
Yeah... They got my eye.
一時的なものだと思うが
まずいな…。
I think it's temporary,
but this is bad.
敵は不死の忍刀七人衆。
対して　俺たちは　ボロボロ。
Our enemy is the reanimated
Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist,
and we're in terrible shape...
絶体絶命というやつだ。
ガイ…。
This is really bad.
Guy!
俺はな　これまで　こうしたピンチを
何度か切り抜けてきたが→
I've survived many
tough situations like this.
そのたびに思い出すことがある。
There's something
I remember every time...
((カカシ：クナイが３本に　起爆札１枚。
Three kunai knives and
one paper bomb...
たったこれだけか。
This is all we have...
（リン）外は　岩の精鋭部隊に
完全に包囲されているわ。
The Stone's best men have us
completely surrounded outside.
ああ　朝一番で
攻めてくるに違いない。
Yeah... They're going to attack us
first thing in the morning.
な～に　心配するには及ばん。
There's no need to worry!
俺には　この拳がある。
I have my fists.
忍具の不足など関係ない。
It doesn't matter
if we're short on ninja tools.
みごと
敵の包囲を突破してみせよう。
Let's break through
the enemy lines.
そもそも　お前がその過剰な自信で
先行したために→
Your overconfidence is what got us
stuck here in the first place.
俺たちが
ここに孤立することになったんだ。
わかってるのか？
勝手な行動は慎め！
Don't you get it?
Don't do anything on your own.
なに辛気臭いこと言ってんだ！
Why are you being such a bore?!
よ～し！　それならば
今度のライバル対決は→
Our next rival challenge is whether
俺が　包囲網を
突破できるかどうかに…。
I can break through
the enemy lines.
命令違反は　忍のクズだ！
Shinobi who defy orders are scum!
隊長である　俺の命令が
聞けないというのなら→
I'm your captain, and if you
can't follow my orders, leave.
忍なんか　やめちまえ！
俺は　もうあんな思いは
こりごりなんだ。
I... just don't want that to
ever happen again.
カカシ　あなた…。
Kakashi, you...
アチャッ！
《そうだ　ついて来い！
That's right. Follow me.
俺が囮となり　敵を引きつければ→
I'll be a decoy.
If the enemy is drawn to me,
それだけ　２人が助かる
可能性は高くなる》
you'll have a greater chance
of escaping.
木ノ葉の碧い猛獣　マイト・ガイ！
I'm Might Guy, the Noble Blue Beast
of the Hidden Leaf!
ただでは死なんぞ！
I don't die easily!
なっ！
What?!
《まだだ！
I'm not done yet!
まだだ！
Not yet!
少なくとも夜明けまでは
時を稼がねば！》
I need to buy time until dawn!
（みんな）ハハハッ！
《すまん　カカシ
お前の言うとおり俺は→
Sorry, Kakashi...
As you said, I'm probably not
suited to being a shinobi...
忍には
向いていないのかもしれんな》
カカシ！
話は　あとだ。
Kakashi?!
We'll talk later!
ここを突破するぞ！
Let's get out of here!
ハァッ　ハァッ　ハァッ…。
さすがにチャクラ切れだ。
We're all out of chakra.
もう大技は使えない。
We can't use
any big techniques anymore.
カカシ　なぜ来た？
Kakashi... Why did you come?
お前が命令に背いたからさ。
Because you defied my orders.
俺は忍には向かないか？
いや。
I'm not worthy of being
a shinobi, am I?
No...
忍の世界では命令は絶対。
In the Shinobi World,
orders are absolute...
だがな　その命令違反が→
But if you defied orders to save
the life of your friends...
仲間の命を守るためだとしたら…。
それを見抜けないようじゃ
隊長失格だ。
And if I couldn't tell the difference
between the two,
I'd be a failure as a captain.
お前…。
You...
それに　案外　お前の作戦は
よかったのかもしれん。
Besides, I think your plan
could have gone really well.
こうして敵を
引きつけることはできた。
We've been able to draw
the enemy away like now.
今頃　リンは
本隊に合流できたはずだ。
Rin should have regrouped with
the main squad by now.
あとは…。
All that's left is...
《なんとかコイツだけでも…》
I have to take care of him...
まずいぞ　ガイ！
This is bad! Guy!
岩の忍たち
広域術式を使うつもりだ。
Stone Shinobi...
They use jutsu formulas
that cover a wide area.
お前のチャクラは
もう尽きているはずでは…。
D-Didn't you run out of chakra?
千鳥！
Chidori!
ハァッ　ハァッ　ハァッ…。
《千鳥で雷を切り裂いただと？
He cut through a lightning bolt
with Chidori?
チャクラだって空っぽのはずなのに》
I thought he was out of chakra!
大丈夫か？　カカシ。
Are you all right, Kakashi?
不思議なもんだな。
How strange...
もう空っぽだと思っていた
チャクラも→
I thought I was out of chakra...
仲間を助けようと思うと
どこからか出てきやがる。
But when I thought about
saving my friends,
it came out of nowhere.
お前は休んでいろ　カカシ。
あとは俺がやる。
You should rest, Kakashi.
I'll handle the rest.
いや　お前だって
走れる足じゃないだろ？
But you can't run on those legs...
足がダメなら腕を使うさ。
If I can't use my legs,
I'll use my arms.
それでもダメなら　指でも口でも。
If I can't use that,
I'll use my fingers or my mouth...
友を救うためなら
最後まで　あがきまくってやる。
and struggle all the way until
the end to save my friends.
今のお前のようにな。
Just like you did now...
(友ね…))
Friend, huh?
見えない目で無理をするなよ
カカシ。
You can't see.
Don't push yourself, Kakashi.
見えなければ音で感じるさ。
If I can't see,
I'll sense things by sound.
それでもダメなら　ニオイでも皮膚でも。
If I can't do that,
I'll use smell or even my skin...
友を救うためなら
最後まで　あがきまくってやるさ。
and struggle all the way
until the end to save my friends.
お前も　あのときのことを…。
You remember that time too...
Let's go!
行くぞ！
おう！
Yeah!
来いよ。
C'mon!
チッ！
ハァーッ！
おっと！
チッ！
ハァーッ！
（２人）かかってこい。
Let's do this!
なめるな！
Don't underestimate me!
（カカシ）お前とのライバル対決を
繰り返してきたのも→
It seems like repeating
our rival challenge
ムダではなかったようだな。
（ガイ）ん？
wasn't a waste of time, after all.
（カカシ）見えずとも　お前の動きが
手に取るようにわかる。
Even if I can't see you,
I know exactly where you are!
お前の動きに合わせることで→
By matching your movements...
敵の動きまでも
見えるかのようだ。
I can even tell where the enemy is.
It's as if I can see.
邪魔だ！
You're in the way!
おめえのほうこそ消えろ！
You should disappear!
んだと！
おめえから先に始末してやる！
I'll deal with you first!
仲間を仲間とも思わぬお前らは…。
You don't think of your comrades
as comrades...
はなから俺たちの敵ではない。
You were never a match for us!
うるせえ！
Shut up!
変わり身だと？
Substitution Jutsu?
とりゃ～！
バカ！　これじゃよけられねえ。
You idiot!
I can't dodge it!
《やったのか？》
Did we succeed?
ちくしょう！
Damn it...
こうなりゃ
チマチマした戦いは終わりだ。
I'm done with this stupid fight!
離れろ　カカシ！
Get back, Kakashi!
俺の爆刀ごと
あたりいちめんドカンよ！
I'll use my Explosion Blade
to blow up this whole area.
テメエ　そんなことしたら
いくら不死身でも→
We may be immortal,
but if you do that we'll die!
死んじまうだろう！
んなもん　やってみりゃわかる！
We won't know until we try!
影縛りの術！
Shadow Stitching Jutsu!
う…　動けねえ。
I-I can't move!
（ラン）カカシ隊長！
Captain Kakashi!
封印班を連れてきましたよ。
I've brought the Sealing Team!
You can see again, Kakashi?
視力が戻ったのか？　カカシ。
ああ。
Yeah...
封印班は　この２人の封印を頼む。
Seal these two away.
はっ！
Yes, sir!
お二人なら
必ずや敵をとってくれると→
I knew that you two
would get revenge!
信じていました。
((て　撤退だ！
W-Withdraw!
(間に合ったわね　ガイ　カカシ！))
You made it just in time,
Guy and Kakashi!
忍の力とは　己のためではなく→
When a shinobi uses his powers
for his friends rather than himself,
仲間のために使われたとき→
何倍もの力を発揮する。
his power multiplies.
それを　俺は　あのとき学んだ。
That's what I learned back then.
仲間のためならば→
Even I can produce
unfathomable power for my friends...
計り知れぬ力を
発揮することができる→
不思議なものだとな。
It's strange.
ああ　そのとおりだ。
Yeah... That's right.
そして皆　それぞれがこの戦争で
それを感じ取っているはずだ。
I think everyone is feeling
that way in this war.
さあ　他の小隊を
さがしにいきましょう。
Come on,
let's go look for the other platoons.
そうだな。
みんなの力を貸してくれ。
Yeah.
Please help, everyone!
（みんな）お～！
– Yes, sir!
I wonder why I can't fly
nande kanaa sora ga tobenai no wa
even though in my dreams, I have wings
yume no naka no boku wa hane ga haeten no ni
I'm going to surpass my limits and leave this place
genkai wo koete tobidasou koko kara
I'll drive away my loneliness with you
samishisa fuki tobasu kimi to kimi to
"I love you" and "good bye" have disappeared
i love you mo sayonara mo ienakatta
leaving me here incomplete
koko ni fukanzen na boku dake wo nokoshite
you still haven't taught me the song of love
ai no uta kimi ni mada tsutaetenai yo
of this dazzling world
dokomademo mabushiku kagayaku sekai wo
of this song
kono uta wo
Ameyuri Ringo...
One of the Seven Ninja Swordsmen
of the Mist.
Wielder of the Lightning Blade,
the Fang.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
What sort of person is
this Ameyuri?
美空ひばりです。
Stop hiding!
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Isn't there anyone here that can
send shockwaves through my heart?
Oh wait... there is someone here
who'll come at me!
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Lightning Blade: Ameyuri Ringo!"
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１１組の皆さんによる→
I'm never going to let you go.